Guide to the Van Cleef Family papers, 1841-1935
Van Cleef Family papers, 1841-1935
- Series VIII. Mynderse Van Cleef and Cornell University
  - Cornell Forest Plantation Fire, 1915-1918 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between M. Van Cleef and former Cornell President Andrew Dickson White, 1915 and 1918 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Ontario Power Company, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Automobile accident relating to Cornell University, 1917-1918 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Delinquency Committee, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Cornell University's Semi-Centennial Endowment, 1919-1920 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Cornell University's Semi-Centennial Endowment, 1919-1921 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Cornell University's Semi-Centennial Endowment, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Cornell University-copies of correspondence from J.G. Schurman regarding Cornell court cases, 1911 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Cornell University-miscellaneous papers and opinions, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Cornell University-miscellaneous court cases, 1911 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Cornell University-miscellaneous court cases and map, 1911 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Cornell University-miscellaneous court cases, 1875-1878 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Proposed revision of the statutes of Cornell University, 1916 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Documents concerning the William H. Sage Pension Fund, 1916 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Statutes of Cornell University's Board of Trustees letters from J.G. Schurman and Judge Frank H. Hiscock to Mynderse Van Cleef, 1914-1915 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Cornell University's Board of Trustees, 1913-1914 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence from William Mann to Mynderse Van Cleef, 1917-1923 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Joseph Nagler versus Cornell University, 1917-1923 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Loomis Laboratory property, 1913-1919 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence concerning the Cornell medical college, 1913-1919 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Raymond Concrete Pile Company, 1913-1919 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence from Francis J. Schleicher, 1913-1919 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Louis Davis against Cornell University, 1913-1919 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Westchester Tile and Trust Company, 1933-1935 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Cornell University Board of Trustees, 1933-1935 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence from Cornell President Livingston Farrand and miscellaneous matters concering the Cornell University Board of Trustees, 1932-1933 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's miscellaneous matters concerning Cornell University, 1931 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's miscellaneous matters concerning Cornell University, including correspondence with President J.G. Schurman, 1920-1925 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous Cornell University matters, wills, estates, settlements etc., 1919 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - M. Van Cleef's miscellaneous Cornell University matters, wills, estates, settlements etc., 1919 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - A photograph of M. Van Cleef in his law office, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Cornell University budget materials, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - William H. Sage to Mynderse Van Cleef regarding Willard Fiske funeral, 1905-01 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Louis Hamburger versus Cornell University, 1920-1922 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Louis Hamburger versus Cornell University, 1919 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Louis Hamburger versus Cornell University, 1916-1921 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Louis Hamburger versus Cornell University, 1916-1919 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - A letter to M. Van Cleef from Martha Van Rensselaer (Dean of the College of Home Economics), 1916-1923 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between Cornell President J.G. Schurman and Dean Albert R. Mann from the College of Agriculture pertaining to making the school of Home Economics it sown identity as the College of Home Economics, 1916-1923 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Various matters concerning the New York State College of Agriculture and the New York State Veterninary College, 1916-1923 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - New York State College of Agriculture miscellaneous matters [correspondence between M. Van Cleef and Dean A.R. Mann], 1918-1920 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - NY State College of Agriculture-including correspondence between M. Van Cleef, President J.G. Schurman and Dean A.R. Mann, 1916-1918 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Bristol House, Group Insurance, Olyphant-Thousand Islands Property, Contributions by classes through Cornellian Council, 1927-1931 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - The will of Mary Crittenden Percy, 1929-1930 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - The Van Cleef Memorial Library, 1929-1930 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous materials on the dredging of Beebe Lake; registration of women students, Phi Gamma Delta; license on dogs; the will of George Le Fevre; Fraternity houses on campus,and a proposed amendment concerning the Cornell Board of Trustees, 1929-1930 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Cornell University and NYC hostpital, the establishment of the Cornell Medical College in NYC, 1929-1930 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Durant Estate; leases Phi Upsicon and Sigma Phi, Henry Shaler Williams Memorial; Humphrey Paint co. Loan; University of Puerto Rico-C.U; Contract with the Associated Gas and Electric Col, Property of Whittaker Heiss on Stewart Ave., Ithaca, 1927-1929 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - M. Van Cleef's lecture notebook from Columbia Law School, New York City, Oct. 1875 (Box 33)
  - Lecture notebook entitled "History of an Action", Oct. 1875 (Box 33)
  - Lecture notebook, Apr. 1876 (Box 33)
  - Criminal law and lecture notebook (Box 33)
  - Lecture notebook entitled "The Method of Preparing Cases for an Agreement", Oct. 1875 (Box 33)
  - Guide to the Cornell University, 1920 (Box 33)
  - The Cornell University Registers (Box 33)
    - 1889-1890
    - 1890-1891
    - 1891-1892
    - 1892-1893
  - Everybody's Magazine, May 1906, Vol. XIV, No. 5 (Box 33)
  - A rock with the words Delt's Ex '73 painted on it (Box 33)
  - Claims of Cornell University against pesons: J.D. Stoup & Co., NYC; F.E. Bucklor, Cortland, NY, 1921-1922 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Claims against Cornell University by sundry persons: S. Corollo; A. Corbin, Smith-Doracy; Forms of bequest to Cornell University, 1919-1924 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural college: miscellaneous matters, opinion; re. Right of commissioner of education to execute contracts for the erection of state buildings for state colleges, 1923-1927 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Opinion of attorney general re. workmen's compensation law re. the authority of cons. of ed, 1923-1927 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Corning Glass Fellowship, 1923-1927 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with A.R. Mann and Martha Van Rensselaer, 1923-1927 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - F.C. Cornell coal yard matter and forest park Hudson Navigation Co., N.C. Monk Manuscripts, "Robert Boyd Ward" Gift report of planning commission with map; Cornell U. building valuations; Sage block lease; Houses of William Azliett Smith; house of David F. Hoy, 1915-1929 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Pension to C.E. Cornell and wife (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - A.D. White estate: statement of net income from real estate (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Jersey City lots, 1915-1929 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Cornell proposal Schoharie Farm and Fall Creek Bed, 1920-1921 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Delta Chi: Cornell University, 1921 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - The Estate of John McMullen, 1921-1927 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - The Estate of Benno Loewy, 1920-1924 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Arnold Haulton (Est. Goldwin Smith); Conveyance of nursing at Home Mission property-Canadian Red Cross Society, 1920-1924 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Claim of Mrs. Linger for personal injuries, etc., 1921 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - C.W. Wason, Chinese Library (Cleveland Trust Company correspondence), 1918-1924 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence; George F. Hewitt Jr.; Furnishing steam heat to Cornell fraternitites; Ithaca Gun Co. with water power; W.R. Robinson and taxation; J. duPratt White re. claim with William H. Schmidloff; claim against the estate of Michae F. Dimburger Jr; Water works opinion; Furnishing water to Forest Home; Claim of the city for damage for depositing silt in Fall Creek; Budget 1931-1932; C.U. medical college; alterations in the library, 1927-1932 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Jervis Langdon (concerning Charles William Wason) and James H. Pierce (concerning William Flint), 1913-1924 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - College of Law Professors, 1921 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Hilda Brownheim vs. Dr. Eleanor Murphy and Cornell University Medical College, 1925 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Improvements to the President of Cornell University's house, 1921 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - The taxation of Cornell University, 1922-1926 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Claims for injuries to animals after a vaccine (anthrax) prepared for Veterninary College, 1921-1923 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Cornelian Council, 1925-1926 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Claims of Cornell University against the estate of W. Horace Schimidlapp, 1931 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Louis Hamburger vs. Cornell University, 1917-1925 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control at Cornell University, 1934 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Inauguration of Cornell President Livingston Farrand; pension agreement with President Farrand, 1921-1926 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Cushings Manual of Parliamentary Practice for Deliberative Assembilies (Box 34)
  - Regular term calendar for the state of Michigan (Box 34)
  - Annual Report of the chief enginner of the Ithaca Fire Department (Box 34)
  - The Bookman: an illustrated magazine of literature and life, Mar., Apr., May 1914 (Box 34)
  - Surrogate's court in Tompkin's country in the matter of the settlement of the estate of Ezra Cornell (Box 34)
  - "Spring Day Big Double Show" pamphlet: for the athletic fund at Cornell University, May 17, 1907 (Box 34)
  - Savage Club program booklet: "Ithaca Band Annual Benefit", Dec. 5, 1903 (Box 34)
  - Court of appeals in the state of New York in the matter of the final accounting and judicial settlement of the accounts of Ithaca Trust Company as testamentary Trustee of Frank J. Enz, argued by Sherman Peer (Box 34)
  - The final judicial settlement of the estate of Ezra Cornell, 1917-1925 (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous house plans and a drawing of the Kappa Alpha Fraternity House (Box 34)
- Series IX. The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef
  - The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef, 1876-1891 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef, 1887 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef, 1888-1890 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef, 1902 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef, 1903-1927 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - The Estate of Elizabeth Van Cleef, 1927 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - The Last Will and Testament of Elizabeth Van Cleef, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Series X. Mynderse Van Cleef's personal and family materials
  - M. Van Cleef's mortgages, 1905-1916 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - M. Van Cleef's mortgages, 1911-1916 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - M. Van Cleef's mortgages, 1915-1916 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - M. Van Cleef's bank statements and balance sheets, 1912-1913 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - M. Van Cleef's bank statements and balance sheets, 1916-1917 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - M. Van Cleef's bank statements and balance sheets, 1918-1919 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - M. Van Cleef's day book (Box 11)
  - Check stubs (three bound books), 1908-1920 (Box 11)
  - M. Van Cleef's mortgages, 1911-1916 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings from The Cornell Daily Sun, The Ithaca Republican and the Ithaca Daily Journal, 1886 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Documents and letters of Alexander and Charles Van Cleef, 1868-1886 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Picture of Eugenia (11 years old) and Jeanette (10 year old) Van Cleef-daughters of M. Van Cleef, 1898 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper article concerning the wedding of Charles E. Treman to Mary A. Bott, 1900-1924 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings and articles, 1900-1924 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "History of Jan Van Cleef of New Utrecht, L.Il, NY", 1909 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Lists of names invited to parties and teas and a wedding invitation (Louis Sumner and Louis Chapman Ralston and Elizabeth Williams and Duncan Campbell Lee), 1915-1917 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Article concerning the Van Cleef memorial law library, Oct. 7, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper articles concerning the death of William H. Van Cleef (cousin of Mynderse Van Cleef), Nov. 22-23, 1934 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper articles concerning the dedication of a bandstand in Seneca Falls, NY (Mynderse Van Cleef), 1924 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence concerning M. Van Cleef's bandstand memorial in Seneca Falls, NY, 1924 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper articles pertaining to M. Van Cleef, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence to M. Van Cleef, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - M. Van Cleef's blank bank statements (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - M. Van Cleef's papers concerning the development of Ithaca's Independant Phone Company and the ensuing dispute with Federal Telephone and Telegraph, Apr. 1900-Aug. 1902 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - M. Van Cleef's papers concerning Ithaca's Independant Phone Company, Oct. 1902-Dec. 1910 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - M. Van Cleef's papers concerning Ithaca's Independant Phone Company, 1911-1915 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Vouchers etc. for M. Van Cleef's new house and stable, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Vouchers etc. for M. Van Cleef's new house and stable, 1904-1906 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Vouchers etc. for M. Van Cleef's new house and stable, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Vouchers etc. for M. Van Cleef's new house and stable, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Vouchers etc. for M. Van Cleef's new house and stable, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Vouchers etc. for M. Van Cleef's new house and stable, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Vouchers etc. for M. Van Cleef's new house and stable, 1902 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - M. Van Cleef's undated court documents (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - History and Rhyms of the Lost Battalion (Box 24)
  - A bound scrapbook of miscellaneous newspaper articles and clippings (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous postcards addressed to Jeanette Van Cleef (daughter of M. Van Cleef) (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous receipts and checks (Box 24)
  - Letter to Mynderse Van Cleef from Andrew Carnegie, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - A luncheon invitation to M. Van Cleef and the Cornell Board of Trustees, Jan. 10, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Dinner invitation in honour of Dr. Andrew D. White and the members of the Cornell University Board of Trustees, Jan. 18, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - A certificate honoring M. Van Cleef's presence at a dinner inauguration for Cornell President Livingston Farrand, Oct. 20, 1921 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Programs, menus etc. of M. Van Cleef as a Cornell Board of Trustee member, 1913-1921 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Signed Christmas card from Mr. and Mrs. Andrew D. White (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Ithaca miscellany, 1905-1925 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Notes by M. Van Cleef in A. D. White's Outlines of a Course of Lectures on History..., 1872-1873 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings, anecdotes etc. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings-poems (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings-obituaries (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Picture of M. Van Cleef with some members of the Cornell Board of Trustees (Box 26)
  - Photograph of Mr. Louis Agassiz (Box 26)
  - A bound black scrapbook (Box 26)
  - Two ornately decorated photo albums (Box 26)
  - Three bound photographs (Box 26)
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's ledger, 1905-1915 (Box 27)
- Series XI. Scrapbooks
  - Jeanette Van Cleef's scrapbook, Sept. 1909-Nov. 1913 (Box 30)
  - Jeanette Van Cleef's scrapbook-documentation of her time spent at Mrs. Dow's School in Briarcliff, NY, Oct. 1906-1909 (Box 31)
  - Eugenia Van Cleef's scrapbook, Sept. 1908-1911 (Box 31)
  - Eugenia Van Cleef's scrapbook-she graduated in 1904 from Ithaca High School and would go on to attend Vassar College, 1900-1905 (Box 31)
  - Jeanette Van Cleef's scrapbook-contains programs from plays, operas and musical concets. Numerous invitaions, newspaper clippings, pins and dried flowers are all mementos from various social activities, 1900-1906 (Box 31)
- Series XII. Alexander Van Cleef's Business and Professional Correspondence
  - Papers of Alexander Van Cleef (Mynderse's father) (Box 4)
  - Estate of John C. Stowell (cash book) (Box 4)
  - Estate of Calvin D. Stowell by M. Van Cleef (3 bound books) (Box 4)
  - 1869 Bank Book (Box 4)
  - A bound copy of M. Van Cleef's letters, (1902-1906) (Box 5)
  - Alexander Van Cleef's ledger, 1862-1878 (Box 5)
  - Daily calendar, 1883-1886 (Box 5)
  - Alexander Van Cleef's ledger, 1862-1878 (Box 5)
  - Alexander Van Cleef's ledger, 1857 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Daniels, Mynderse Co., Seneca Falls correspondence, receipts and orders concerning Alexander Van Cleef, 1857 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Daniels, Mynderse Co., Seneca Falls correspondence, receipts and orders including canal boat, 1855-1861 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - A.M. Van Cleef and Co. correspondence, personal correspondence, receipts etc., 1862 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - A.M. Van Cleef and Co. correspondence, business correspondence, receipts etc., 1863 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - A.M. Van Cleef's business and personal correspondence, 1864 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - A.M. Van Cleef's business and personal correspondence, 1864 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - A.M. Van Cleef's business and personal correspondence, 1865 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - A.M. Van Cleef's correspondence and agreement, 1866-1867 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Darrow Lay of Clayton, Michigan to A.M. Van Cleef, 1872 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence from Darrow Lay of Clayton, Michigan to A.M. Van Cleef, 1873 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence from Darrow Lay of Clayton, Michigan to A.M. Van Cleef, 1874 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Darrow Lay of Clayton, Michigan to A.M. Van Cleef, 1875 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - A.M. Van Cleef's business correspondence, 1876 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous undated receipts, correspondence and a newspaper from 1874 (Seneca County Courier) (Box 32, Folder 15)
- Series XIII. Mapcase
  - Mynderse Van Cleef's Cornell University Diploma, 1874 (Folder 1)
  - Charles Van Cleef's Certificate of Membership into the American Institute of Homeopathy, 1884 (Folder 1)
  - A certificate acknowledging Mynderse Van Cleef membership into the Ithaca Fire Department, 1888 (Folder 1)
  - A certificate acknowledging that Mynderse Van Cleef is admitted into the District Court for the state of New York, 1882 (Folder 1)
  - Van Cleef house plans and specs, 1902 (Folder 2)